Be careful who you pray to.
The Unholy is a horror, mystery film directed by Evan Spiliotopoulos.
Alice is a young hearing-impaired girl who, after a supposed visitation from the
Virgin Mary, is inexplicably able to hear, speak and heal the sick.
As word spreads and people from near and far flock to witness her miracles, a disgraced
journalist hoping to revive his career visits the small New England town to investigate.
When terrifying events begin to happen all around, he starts to question if these
phenomena are the works of the Virgin Mary or something much more sinister.
Gerry Fenn, played by Jeffrey Dean Morgan.
Alice, played by Cricket Brown.
Father Hagan, played by William Sadler.
Natalie Gates, played by Katie Aselton.
Bishop Gyles, played by Cary Elwes.
Delgarde, played by Diogo Morgado.
The Unholy is a 2021 American supernatural horror film written, produced, and directed by Evan
Spiliotopoulos (in his directorial debut), based on the 1983 novel Shrine by James Herbert.
Produced by Sam Raimi through his Ghost House Pictures banner, it stars Jeffrey Dean Morgan,
Katie Aselton, William Sadler, Diogo Morgado, Cricket Brown, and Cary Elwes.
The film follows on a disgraced journalist (Morgan) who discovers a series of seemingly divine miracles in a small New
England town and uses them to resurrect his career, though those "miracles" may have a much darker source.
The project was announced in December 2018 under the working title Shrine,
with Sony Pictures adapting Herbert's novel of the same name.
The cast was announced between 2018 and 2020, with principal photography commencing in Boston,
but on March 14, 2020, filming was suspended because of the COVID-19 pandemic.
The Unholy was theatrically released in the United States on April 2, 2021.
Despite receiving negative reviews from critics, the film was considered a box office
success, grossing $31 million worldwide against a budget of $10 million.
The film explores themes of witch, melancholy, demon, mysterious, shocking.
The tone is dark and mind_bending.